[Music]
innovate in a icrc a Prudential Life
Insurance and CNBC tv18 presents mission
insurer India life insurance for all the
Indian insurance sector both life and
non-life have grown at a rapid clip but
what hasn't grown is the penetration of
insurance in India life insurance
penetration stands at 2.7 percent
according to the last Economic Survey
numbers this compares with a global
average of three point four seven
percent one full percentage point higher
other Asian countries like Malaysia at
four point seven percent Thailand at
five point four percent
China again at four point seven seven
percent have all better insurance
penetration than India has but more
important is that even those who buy
insurance protection in India don't buy
enough protection the protection gap as
it is called in India is calculated at
eight point five trillion dollars while
comparably it's just one trillion
dollars a gap for say Indonesia and
Thailand both comparable countries so
how does one develop the insurance
sector what can companies do what can
industry bodies do what can the
government and the regulator do that's
the question we are asking today and our
elite panels to answer these questions
includes mr. Lilly shot a whole time
member on the board of in died the
insurance regulator
Puneet than that deputy managing
director I see a few life insurance mr.
beebe anakim secretary general life
insurance counsel and Yash dajia the CEO
of policy Bazar gentlemen thank you very
much for sparing time for us
mr. Satya well as the senior boss that
we start with you
insurance penetration at two point seven
other Asian countries are almost double
at four point seven percent is this only
a product of low per capita income or is
it more ignorant how do we calculate
penetration penetration
is the insurance to GDP ratio now the
insurance premium if it increases
substantially at a faster rate than the
GDP obviously the penetration will go
and since GDP is growing reasonably well
at six seven percent for the last couple
of years obviously unless insurance
premium grows at a higher rate than that
the penetration will not go up and let
me tell you over a period of time it is
seem that the insurance penetration has
been increasing though not at a rate or
the desire desired rate but it has been
increasing and that is a good sign okay
what would you say beneath to that is
this that because of the unaffordability
factor a lot of people are not buying
protection or is it that you know we
haven't even reached the message I think
it's a combination of everything the the
most important of course is the
awareness levels the point you made
about message I think that is
responsibility for all of us together to
ensure that but if I look at it
historically I think it is also a bit to
do with affordability you know when when
the income levels in a country are low
people are worried about basic
necessities also India traditionally
culturally had a very strong joint
family system where does insurance come
in insurance comes if you are not there
who takes care of your dependents in the
whole joint family system you know the
rest of the family would take care of
your dependents like you took care of
their dependent I think as families are
becoming nuclear as income levels are
increasing at least that part is getting
taken care of and I think right now the
single most important agenda for all of
us is to increase the awareness levels
and I think government is playing its
role regulator is playing its own
industry is playing its role
distributors are playing the role but
clearly there's a long way to go for all
of us okay what do you what would you
say mr. Monica is it that a large number
of people are not even aware that they
have to buy this product it is
affordable but they are not buying
protection the average premium per
policy is only twenty two thousand
rupees whereas the affordable income of
following Denise
more than 2 lakh rupees when he is
having disposable income more than 2
lakh rupees and he is able to you can
either have you only twenty two thousand
rupees at the premium there is enough
room for them to go for higher higher
higher number of policies terminals
policies are normal policies all the
things what I can say awareness is very
matured are in India are life insurances
honorable Prime Minister Modi ji has
come out with the PM JJ big ways that is
the other booster for the awareness it
is ability also is there under
penetration to the protection gap the
problem is not just that those who can
offered are buying are not buying
insurance but they don't seem to be
buying enough insurance yes
what what do you how do you look at this
problem why is it that people you know
should be insuring themselves for
probably a crore their affordability is
there but they think probably 10 lakhs
is enough that seems to be the bigger
problem isn't it I totally agree I think
the bigger issue is when a family loses
that breadwinner and it doesn't happen
it should never happen but but in life
it does happen when that happens the
economic void created is very deep and
people do not fully appreciate the
severity of that and that is not
communicated enough also I think we as
an industry have failed at communicating
the size of that void see typically if
you look at the insurance industry today
roughly 97 percent of all premium is
going towards some form of savings
products whereas you know what is going
towards pure protection is very very
small and I think that is the reason as
an industry
we haven't done enough to educate the
consumer on that need and that void and
that void as Sir pointed out in a
nuclear family today I have so many
situations where somebody some friend
has expired somebody has expired and
they are in a financially difficult
position and then friends get together
put some money together etc but it's
very little compared to the needs the
long-term that family and I think that
gap is whatever the numbers say this
2.7% etc actually means nothing that gap
is way too wide right today I would say
they are about 1 million 2 million pure
protection policy is being sold in this
country which is just too small what is
it as a percentage of total insurance
and it's I think as number of policy
will be 3 percent and that is the reason
the biggest issue you are having is a
summer short to premium difference
people are paying a premium but that
premium is not going towards the summer
shorts in yeah and the protection is is
the reason for this industry so I think
somewhere that peace is not being
focused sufficiently well you know who
need the numbers that we were given from
the industry is that there is a gap of
eight and a half trillion dollars in
terms of protection needed but
protection actually bought how do you
measure this number in the first place
there are multilateral agencies which do
this so this particular report is a
report I think by Swiss Re they do this
once in five years for various countries
in the world so protection gap just for
everybody's understanding simply means
what is the required sum assured in the
country - the actual sum assured and it
includes group insurance individual
insurance everything and how do you
measure what is the required semester I
think there are various ways of
calculating human life value etcetera it
is it is using that and on top of that
they also add depending on the low the
retail loans the morgue age etcetera so
there is supposed to be a cover on that
also so you measure it that way and on
that metric clearly it's a staggering
number and you yeah she spoke about the
fact that one or two million people have
ever bought a protection policy I can
pet one or two percent of that one or
two million have bought ID quit first is
less number of people are buying and
those who are buying a not taking
adequate cover for themselves you know
the whole concept is very simple if you
are not around do you have enough for
your family to live the kind of life
they would like to live okay that that
question is not asked in such simple
terms
but mr. SOT if what would be you know
the way to resolve this is this
something which the regulator can do or
is this the responsibility of the
industry itself you know the industry
body and the companies which comprise
the industry see that actually I will
not say that
this is the job only of a regulator it's
the government the regulator as he said
you know all of us have to evolve it and
take it forward now the question is why
why is it that people do not understand
that there is a protection gap there are
many reasons for this and the main is
many times in India because of the
social structure that we have because of
the family you know attachment that we
have we always think that whatever I
will say should go to my kith and kin to
my children that is not the case with
Western countries as a result of which
they think that okay so long as I am
Alive I should get protection so that my
family means my wife not even beyond
that should get adequate money as in
case of insurance we say that insurance
what is insurance it's the human life
value is the value of her money
producing machine economic value yes a
human being who is producing who is
learning that is his you know he's a
machine it should be a replacement of
that yes and from that point of
protection there is no substitute for
protection and the protection can be
given only by insurance no other savings
product
neither mutual friend nor bank deposit
nothing and you your protection to that
extent when people say that the return
on it should have suspected law the
question is how do you calculate return
if a person died is immediately of
taking a policy just imagine what will
be the rate of return but nobody wants
to die and actually insurance is not a
we say that it is not for those who die
but it is for those who survive so after
his death those who are dependent on him
it is for them but why hasn't the
industry taken the effort to educate
this part I mean it's a cheaper product
pure protection term insurance why has
the industry you know concentrated on
savings and endowment most of the
advertisements don't directly tell you
that protection is cheap and protection
is necessary the message doesn't come
across mister Monica are the industry we
are taking all our diverse trade you get
the people as far as I am concerned the
change should come within from me Tina
if a dollar breadwinner is having a real
love and affection for the family in
case if I am not available my family
should live in the same standard of life
if a dolly is have a sense of belonging
to the family automatically the gap can
be bridged quickly it's not that
automatic people you know probably 50
years ago understood what is an FD
product and how it is different from a
savings account people probably in the
last 20 years or ten years have
understood what is the mutual fund
product I know shares that whiskey
somebody else is taking the investment
decision for me nutrition product was
understood I don't think the insurance
product the differentiation between
endowments some short money back and
pure protection pure term has been
explained it's probably more
sophisticated more difficult but put it
would you say that the industry can do
more to communicate well certainly I
think we have to take this
responsibility joint conifers for
several reasons that we discussed
earlier you know probably India was not
at the right stage but now you know over
the last two or three years as some of
you would have noticed a lot of our
advertising is around awareness is is
around protection most of us today are
very very focused on that category and
for whatever reason if you have not done
in the past I think it's an opportunity
for all of us to do it now as mr. Manik
um pointed out I think the single
biggest advertising and awareness
building for this country was done by
this government when they launched the
pradhan mantri you know Jeevan Jyoti be
my oshina
the summer shirt may be small but I
think it brought of Irma's levels to the
last mile in the first year of their
launch in 1516 I remember they launched
in the first year of their launch three
crore or
was sold the entire industry and I see
all of us put together memory used to
sell that much in one year and remember
the policy the scheme was open for one
month
it sold 3 crore in the last year the
number at exceeded 5 crore so I think
all of these together will ensure that
as we go ahead awareness increases and
while we increase awareness obviously we
have to work on all the other things
better product better service better
onboarding by tech names matter service
and all of those things ICICI Prudential
life insurance and CNBC tv18 presents
mission insurer India life insurance for
all yes how you at policy bazaar
propagating the idea is there a number
like you know if I'm earning so much at
this stage in life this is the amount I
have to buy is the formula simple enough
and is it getting enough response I'll
just make a slightly controversial
statement here I'll take a person who's
earning 3 lakh rupees let's say the
protection he needs is 30 lakh rupees we
all agree to that that a protection
requires 30 lakh rupees if he buys that
through an investment endowment any
product typically the summer short is 10
times of premium that means he has to
put his entire salary pre-tax into that
product to just get his summer shirt so
it's financially impossible the only way
he can protect and get that adequate
protection is through term insurance now
let's get to term insurance he gets to
buy 30 like a piece of term insurance by
my math that should cost him about 300
to 400 rupees a month that is three
thousand four thousand three hundred
bees a month now a person earning three
lakh rupees can afford three thousand
rupees a month three hundred rupees a
month so protection is not expensive
it's quite cheap it doesn't cost so much
we should not I think this is where I
make a controversial statement I think
we as an industry have been confusing
investment and protection and saying
investment will cause protection it it
cannot it just cannot give adequate
protection because I have to put my
entire income into a policy just to
protect myself which is financially
impossible he's only an awareness issue
or can tax incentives make a difference
no I think it's a it's a lot of things
the biggest thing of course is awareness
but along with that we do need to keep
innovating on for work structures
because
it's from two perspective the BC product
may still be just protection or term
insurance but they can be many variation
whether how long you pay for you know
premium pink term how long is the cover
how do you get payout is it lump sum is
it in various stage do you bundle health
along with it either in the form of
writers or whatever what will be the
form of payment of that so a lot of
product design innovation can be brought
in while ensuring that things are kept
simple number one number two I think
this whole concept of onboarding when
you actually get a customer to agree
after that also it's a very elaborate
process before the customer actually
gets the policy issues you know
especially on hire covers there is
medical requirement there's a lot of
underwriting requirement we have to use
a technology we have to use data
analytics to try and simplify that to be
able to give things literally across the
counter you know so for example our our
vision is that it should be as easy to
buy a life cover as it is to take a RFD
in a bank why should we not do that of
course for that a lot of things I have
to fall in place but I think that is the
second thing the third of course is to
ensure that you know when the moment of
truth comes the claims are indeed paid
and paid fast thanks to the efforts of
iid I think ideas brought a lot of focus
on that on the industry today the claims
payout ratios are very good I think
pretty much the entire industry is 90
percent plus and the good company are 95
percent plus which is really good
because it helps at the same time how
long does it take to pay the claim AIA
days also defined t-80s for that and you
know all of us in the good companies
actually ensure that is less than that
along with all of that I think the the
whole question of awareness has to go on
on and on and on you spoke about tax I
think that is an important element to
some extent there are already some tax
benefits available for the university
but if I look at protection specifically
today you know the indirect tax the main
indirect tax is GST if I buy term
insurance the GST rate is 18% you have
seen how the GST counsel of the
government has progressively brought
down GST rates for various things you
know for luxury items also it is 18% for
something that is necessary it is 18%
there is a category where government
says are essential commodity
where they charge you know the GST rate
is five percent you know if the
government think this is essential they
should encourage it by bringing that and
remember this is a country where there
is no Social Security the government
does not take care of its citizens if
something goes wrong there is no you
know government pension there is no
social security so this is the way to
incentivize
well the millennial generation
automatically solve this problem I mean
we have seen the first offering of
digital term products and it's doing
very well as you said it's probably 30%
of all protection in terms of some
assured do you think the millennial
generation will understand this better
the direction is already very clear in
my opinion and you can have this data
validated 30% of all some Ishod of this
country is now coming with a digital
channel online whether it's the
companies websites where there's people
like us etc etc very big number for such
a large industry so I think the answer
is already there that the consumers want
to buy protection relatively of course
they have to be educated and that is
that is happening
I think the good part is there's a lot
happening at the regulator at the
companies levels people are suddenly
talking about some assured and it's
becoming a priority that was not so if I
look at five seven years ago it is a
less understood industry the protection
part of it it is a very small part of
the industry it is it is a very useful
part of the industry I think everybody
is getting smarter at it where the
regulator's the companies people like us
the consumer it's it's a it's a it's a
Jacob it's it's growing fast that's all
I can say all right just a couple of
words on where do you see the future is
it a Jacob do you think B could a you
know see the industry perhaps doubling
in the next four or five years I think
if we double the protection part in the
next four or five years we would have
seriously underperformed I think the
scope is far far more you know we've
done some research around the world
typically when per capita income of a
country reaches somewhere between 1500
to 2000 dollars there is indeed a very
significant J curve that comes India
just reach that stage and along with all
our things that we are speaking about it
will happen you spoke about the
millennial generation you know one of
the things of this generation is it is
more a consumer
society than a saving society and you
know what do consumers do they borrow
right to buy things when you borrow you
are taking a huge risk simplest thing to
do is take life car along with that
whatever whether it is a personality it
is absolutely happening it is absolutely
happening so today you see you know the
retail credit growth along with that the
rate of growth of the cover part along
well is pretty much in line with that
the other thing that the millennial
generation wants is simplicity and
convenience or you know the currency's
time honestly say if you make things
simple whether through digital channel
at a click of a button or at you know
with one one today there is enough data
you know available in the industry for
us to be able to take those analytical
calls to be able to you know make life
simpler for the consumer and as this
goes along as I said you know I think
the AUM will double in the next five
years but the sum assured can be
multiple times of that you're guessing
yes I also agree with Polly
the only issue is even today I have come
across a lot of educated people so to
say forget of financial literacy or
furniture you guys you were referring to
they say that if you if I buy protection
what is it that I will get if I survive
and then the answer is no they just stay
back okay that is something which needs
to be told repeatedly and where that
this is the product for you
you know you need this product
protection but then what you should
companies are doing okay then let me
have you I will return you the premium
what you have paid if you survive that
is something which is like all these are
the riders which are added to it health
insurance rider cancer protection this
and that they like that so this is
bundling of a product term insurance but
along with that and that is something
which is liked by the Millennials okay
and definitely the term insurance which
is being bought more is by educated not
by less educated so that is something so
as the education level will go up and
the GDP will go up and it is going up
obviously the insurance the protection
the penetration all these parameters
will improve for India okay thank you
very much mr. sati that's extremely well
development itself will help ensure that
citizens are buying adequate protection
and this mission ensured India that I
see I shall prove and CNBC tv18 is
launching today with this show is
exactly trying to achieve that to ensure
that individuals understand how much
protection has to be bought and the
protection part of life insurance finds
its rightful place in a family budget
thank you very much for watching this
special edition RC RC a Prudential Life
Insurance and CNBC tv18 presents mission
insure India life insurance for all
[Music]
innovate in